Dependency injection in FastAPI is a design pattern that allows you to manage dependencies in your application efficiently. It enables you to define functions or classes that provide resources (like database connections, configuration settings, or services) to your route handlers.

In FastAPI, you can declare dependencies using the `Depends` function. This allows you to:

1. **Reuse code**: Share common logic across multiple routes.
2. **Manage lifecycle**: Control the creation and destruction of resources.
3. **Improve testability**: Easily mock dependencies during testing.

Here's a simple example:

```python
from fastapi import FastAPI, Depends

app = FastAPI()

def get_query_param(q: str = None):
    return q

@app.get("/")
async def read_root(query: str = Depends(get_query_param)):
    return {"query": query}
```

In this example, `get_query_param` is a dependency that retrieves a query parameter, and it's injected into the `read_root` route handler.
