FastAPI handles async endpoints using Python's `async` and `await` syntax, allowing for non-blocking I/O operations. When you define an endpoint as an asynchronous function (using `async def`), FastAPI can handle requests concurrently, improving performance, especially under high loads.

Here's a basic example:

```python
from fastapi import FastAPI

app = FastAPI()

@app.get("/items/{item_id}")
async def read_item(item_id: int):
    # Simulate an asynchronous operation, e.g., a database call
    await some_async_function()
    return {"item_id": item_id}
```

In this example, `some_async_function()` would be an asynchronous operation, allowing FastAPI to handle other requests while waiting for it to complete. FastAPI uses an ASGI server (like Uvicorn) to manage these async capabilities efficiently.
